Luis C. Lasso E.

+507-6014-1400 •Panama, Panama • llasso05@gmail.com • https://www.linkedin.com/in/luis-carlos-lasso-escala-8a9061160/

Data Scientist/Data Engineer

Data Management and Analytics | Business Acumen | Business Intelligence

Experienced data professional with more than 7 years of experience in data projects for multiple organizations in the manufacturing industry. Excellent communication skills with tech and business organizations playing multiple data related roles for business transformation processes.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Dell Technologies – Panama, Panama

September 2021 - Present

Data Engineering Advisor

Data engineering support for a set of newly developed applications created to support the marketing organization data processes through data availability and process automation.

- Supported tool global expansion from a Data Engineering and Project Management perspective.
- Maintain stored procedures for customer attributes from internal systems to our application database.
- Developed algorithm configuration pipelines for end users to interact with data science developed algorithms.

Calidad Integral - Panama, Panama

January 2017 - September 2021

Data Science Consultant

Data Engineering and Data Science support for a consultant quality firm that works with different organizations within the pharmaceutical industry.

- Developed SQL database that consumes customer quality complains.
- Stablished specifics KPI's to determine product integrity issues with transportation or storage.
- Created multiple Power Bi dashboards to support organizational review.
- Implemented a time series algorithm to predict and keep track on reported issues trends.

Dell Technologies - Panama, Panama

July 2017 - September 2021

Marketing Funds Controller

Provided business data analysis support for the marketing development program by data storytelling to business leadership. Leading business transformation to automated processes worldwide.

- Implemented Data Warehouse database to automate data collection.
- Developed Power Bi dashboards to support data storytelling for business V.P.'s.

Luis Lasso +507-6014-1400

Developed Time Series algorithm to predict quarterly and yearly marketing expense.

• Automated financial reporting using Python and Selenium.

EDUCATION

IBM with Coursera - United States

Professional Certificate - Data Engineer 2022

Dell-EMC with Pearson – *United States*

Associate of Science - Data Science 2020

Universidad Interamericana de Panama - Panama

Master Degree - Corporate Finance 2016

Universidad Interamericana de Panama - Panama

MBA - Business Administration 2016

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- SQL Querying and database administration.
- ETL/ELT Pipelines.
- Linux Bash.
- Python and R for Data Science.
- Project Management.
- Scrum and Crisp-DM
- Hadoop Ecosystem: Kafka, Airflow, Spark.
- Power Bi and Tableau for business intelligence.
- Mongo NoSQL.
- Tiger graph Database.
- HTML with CSS.
- Strong business acumen and communication skills.
- IBM Cloud for Data Engineering: Cloudant, DB2.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Instituto Verter (Brazil) - Brazil, Sao Paulo

October 26 - 30 2022

Non-Profit Organization (Pro Bono Consulting)

- Created a data strategy for data collection on doctor's appointments with kids in Brazil.
- Virtualized data collection using google drive and Power Bi as the stepping stone for their data strategy.

Junior Achievement - Panama, Panama

Luis Lasso +507-6014-1400

Non-Profit Organization (Teaching the Future)

• Developed a Python basic training for high school students in Panama to complete through Junior Achievement.

• Work with junior achievement designers to gamify this training to make it more attractive for the students.

AWARDS AND HONORS

Dell Analytical Forum Winner - Panama, *Panama*

August 2021

• Developed time series algorithm deployed through Power Bi.

PROFESSIONAL MEMBERSHIPS

- Power Bi User Group Panama
- Global Visual Studio Code Community